what's up everybody this is lauren from
barbin.com and today we have the
nordictrack commercial 1750 with us in
studio it's one of the most popular
treadmills on the market if not the most
popular treadmill on the market it's got
a ton of ifit technology about mid-range
when it comes to pricing high quality
build but that's just the start we're
going to take you along step by step
detail by detail through what's in this
treadmill in our review follow along all
right we have a ton to cover here i'm
going to do a walk around and we're
going to talk about the ifit technology
the build of this treadmill the incline
the decline but if you want a full
review and you want to read it yourself
head to google type in barbin plus
nordictrack 1750 and if you want a full
list of our best treadmills go ahead and
type in barban plus best treadmills and
you'll find everything right there
oh and also if you want to check out the
latest pricing on the nordictrack
commercial 1750 go ahead and click the
link in our description and while you're
at it like and subscribe to barbin's
youtube channel
all right i'm going to give you a quick
overview of what we're working with here
if you come up here
the first thing that you're going to
notice is this 10 inch touchscreen
display
one of the cool things about it you can
pivot it back if you're taller
pivot it down if you're shorter to
adjust to your height
everything ifit related is going to be
right in here
if you come over here you'll see all of
the decline and incline options decline
is actually pretty rare where you don't
see that on a lot of treadmills and this
treadmill declines down to negative
three percent goes all the way up to
fifteen percent
if you come across here you'll find all
your speed options you got one mile per
hour all the way up to 12 miles per hour
right below all of this you'll see two
big speakers and the option for
bluetooth if you connect your phone to
bluetooth you can play music out of
these speakers right on here you'll also
hear all of your ifit instructors
instructions coming through here in the
speakers
if we go right down here you'll see a
two-ply belt it's got a lot of great
grip on it so you're not going to be
falling off this thing it's also a super
smooth ride one of the other really cool
features about this treadmill is it has
adjustable cushioning so if you use this
knob right here turn it you can either
make your surface firmer or softer
depending on what you prefer
come around the back here
lift this thing up
it's got a hydraulic lift system here so
folding it super easy pretty much does
it itself anyone can do it obviously a
lot of the money that you're spending
here is going toward all the cool
technology that's in this treadmill
you've got ifit classes virtual training
destinations around the world if you are
one that likes to take a coach workout
virtually this treadmill is definitely
for you however if you don't enjoy that
as much you want to run outside on your
own you want to run on a tread that
doesn't have a screen staring at you in
the face you can definitely find a
cheaper option out there all right now
let's talk about the build of the
nordictrack commercial 1750. for
starters it's about 81 inches long by 40
inches wide which is pretty big for a
treadmill
it can handle user weight of about 300
pounds and it also weighs about 300
pounds which is pretty heavy but that's
due mostly in part to this bad boy down
here and this steel frame if you go up
from the steel frame you'll find plastic
along the outside here and underneath in
the storage tray these water bottle
holders on either side of this are also
made of plastic so if you put a water
bottle here while you're working out and
you hit those high speeds of 11 or 12 it
can get a bit jiggly so that's just
something to note in addition this tread
also has a pretty powerful 3.75 chp
motor
and even though it's hitting some pretty
high inclines and low declines it stays
quiet as it's going which can be nice if
you're doing early morning workouts or
any workouts late at night okay next up
we're going to talk about the feel of
the nordictrack 1750.
for starters if you're on a treadmill
you're going to want it to be
comfortable if it's not comfortable
you're not going to get on it a whole
lot this right here very comfortable
it's got a lot of great grip it has a
smooth ride and one of the coolest
features that this treadmill has that
not a lot of treadmills have is
adjustable cushioning on top of that you
come up here you have a ton of storage
right here so if you need to bring
anything with you keep it out of the way
from your workout can put it all down
here if you have a water you can put it
on either side in one of these water
bottle holders plus if you ever feel
unsafe you can grip onto this hold this
front handlebar and if you need to stop
your treadmill immediately just pull on
the safety key right here and it'll stop
right away
okay next up we're going to talk about
all of the technology in this treadmill
as you can see this console is pretty
big that's because there's a lot going
on here so let's get into it
on the bottom here you're going to have
on this handlebar two heart rate
monitors where you can put your hands
and test your heart rate whenever you
want to throughout your workout however
this machine doesn't come with a
separate heart rate monitor so if you
need a trust chest strap or something to
put on your wrist to track your heart
rate you're going to have to buy that
separately if you want to use some of
the features within ifit once you come
up here you're going to see speakers
that run along the bottom of the console
these will project your instructor's
words when you're taking a workout or if
you want to connect your phone to
bluetooth you can hook it up and it'll
play music for you however you're not
going to see any of your music on the
screen so if you want to change a song
or something you're going to have to do
that on your phone yourself when you
come across the bottom here you're going
to see two buttons to control the fan so
if you things get a little hot in your
workout you can turn it up turn it down
and now we're going to get into the ifit
technology on this console all right
once you get in here you're going to see
all of the ifit technology available
obviously it's a bit overwhelming
because ifit offers over 16 000 live and
on-demand classes another cool thing
that ifit does is they offer
classes across the world so you could
ifit instructors will take you to
destinations around the world like wales
new zealand and you can take a workout
on screen in that destination with that
instructor if you want to narrow things
down you can click ifit's browse option
go in there type in anything that you're
looking for all the on-demand options
available will pop up there for you to
take if you prefer to take a live class
you can navigate to the live option
along the bottom finally if you want to
get creative you can go into this create
button at the bottom here and build your
own workout at any destination across
the world okay let's talk pricing
obviously pricing can be a huge deal
breaker for people so we want to make
sure that we're covering this topic in
full
for the machine itself you're gonna
spend around nineteen hundred dollars
however prices obviously change over
time so just make sure you're checking
the website when you're purchasing for
the accurate price
in addition to get the full experience
out of this treadmill you're gonna wanna
get that ifit membership it does cost
around four hundred dollars a year or
thirty nine dollars per month so
that's a lot on its own but
nordictrack sometimes offers great deals
where you can get a free year of ifit
with your purchase of the machine so
just make sure you're checking the
website and getting the deal you want
when you're purchasing in addition as
far as warranties go you're going to get
10 years on the frame two years on parts
and one year on labor overall this
treadmill falls right in the middle of
the market when it comes to pricing
you're getting a great deal especially
if you get that one year of ifit for
free with your purchase all right let's
talk pros and cons obviously one of the
biggest pros of this treadmill is all
the technology that comes with it
especially the access to ifit you get
over 16 000 classes that you can take
you'll never get bored when you're
working out
on top of that this has a really cool
decline option you can decline your
tread all the way down to negative 3
that's great for people who are training
for an outdoor race that may need to
mimic the flow of the road or a trail in
addition to that it has adjustable
cushioning so again if you're training
for a road race or a trail race you can
mimic that outdoor feel right here on
your tread as far as cons go one of the
biggest ones is that it doesn't come
with a heart rate monitor you can put
your hands right here test your heart
rate as you go but if you want a
separate heart rate monitor that's
something you're going to have to pay
for separately in addition to that as
you can see it's pretty big so if you're
living in a small space you might need
something smaller than this treadmill
and just a tiny note if you're hitting
top speeds and you put a water bottle in
either of these water bottle holders
it's going to jiggle as you go and make
a little bit of noise
not a huge deal but definitely something
you want to know so let's talk about
what to expect when this treadmill
arrives at your door it's going to come
in a huge box and it's going to weigh
about 300 pounds it's for sure a two-man
job to put this thing together plus it
comes with a lot of parts and not all of
the tools that you need to do the job
it costs 200 to get it delivered and
just for fifty dollars more you can have
it assembled too if i were to do it all
again that's the way i'd go all right
that's a wrap on our nordictrack
commercial 1750 review like i said a ton
of cool ifit technology here over
sixteen 000 classes so you'll never get
bored but this machine does take up
quite a bit of space if you're living in
a small apartment may not be the best
fit for you if you want to read more or
about anything that we covered today go
ahead and google barbin plus nordictrack
commercial 1750 or if you want to check
the pricing click the link below and
while you're at it like and subscribe to
our youtube channel that's it for today
you